var physicsQuestions = [{
        question: "What is the first name of the famous scientist who gave us Newton’s three laws of motion?",
        choices: ["Albert Einstein", "Galileo Galilei", "Michael Faraday", "Isaac Newton"],
        answer: "Isaac Newton"
    },
    {
        question: "Bolometer is used to measure?",
        choices: ["Temperature", "Frequency", "Velocity", "Wavelength"],
        answer: "Temperature"
    },
    {
        question: "Which one of the following has the highest value of specific heat?",
        choices: ["Alcohol", "Methane", "Water", "Kerosene"],
        answer: "Water"
    },
    {
        question: "Product of Force and Velocity is called:",
        choices: ["Work", "Energy", "Power", "Momentum"],
        answer: "Power"
    },
    {
        question: "A man presses more weight on earth at:",
        choices: ["leaning Position", "Lying Position", "Standing Position", "Sitting position"],
        answer: "Standing Position"
    },
    {
        question: "If electrical conductivity increases with the increase of temperature of a substance, then it is a:",
        choices: ["Conductor", "Semiconductor", "Insulator", "Carborator"],
        answer: "Semiconductor"
    },
    {
        question: "With the increase of pressure, the boiling point of any substance",
        choices: ["Increases", "Becomes zero", "Decreases", "Remains Same"],
        answer: "Increases"
    },
    {
        question: "The rotational effect of a force on a body about an axis of rotation is described in terms of the",
        choices: ["Centre of gravity", "Centrifugal force", "Moment of force", "Centripetal force"],
        answer: "Moment of force"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the unit of Astronomical Distance?",
        choices: ["Weber", "Lux", "Angstrom", "Light year"],
        answer: "Light year"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the scale used for measuring the intensity of the earthquake?",
        choices: ["Richter Scale", "Quake Scale", "Metric Scale", "Epicentre Scale"],
        answer: "Richter Scale"
    }
];

var mathsQuestions = [{
        question: "You are travelling down the motorway at 60 m/s. How long will it take you to cover a distance of 30,000 metres?",
        choices: ["750 seconds", "50 seconds", "500 seconds", "1050 seconds"],
        answer: "500 second"
    },
    {
        question: "Convert you last answer from seconds to minutes. How many minutes does it therefore take you to travel 30,000 metres at 60m/s?",
        choices: ["8.33 mins", "0.833 mins", "12.5 min", "17.5 mins"],
        answer: "8.33 mins"
    },
    {
        question: "Aamina and Emal Fiza are working on a maths project together, and together they are being paid a total of £10,000 in the ratio 6:4 respectively. How much does Emal get paid?",
        choices: ["£5000", "£6000", "£4000", "£3750"],
        answer: "£4000"
    },
    {
        question: "Emal Fiza suffers from the case of a broken nose and the size of his nose increases by 2.5% each month. If his nose measured 4 cm at the beginning of December, what does his nose measure mid-April?",
        choices: ["4.42 cm", "4.31 cm", "4.20 cm", "4.3 cm"],
        answer: "4.42 cm"
    },
    {
        question: "You are travelling in the shape of a right-handed triangle, with sides measuring - hypotenuse 50m and adjacent 43m. what is the length of the opposite side?",
        choices: ["423 m", "754 m", "534 m", "651 m"],
        answer: "651 m"
    },
    {
        question: "How much does the angle between the given adjacent and hypotenuse in the last question measure?",
        choices: ["50 degrees", "90 degrees", "40.7 degrees", "94.55 degrees"],
        answer: "40.7 degrees"
    },
    {
        question: "What is 567,846 rounded to the nearest 10",
        choices: ["567,800", "567,850", "567,840", "570,000"],
        answer: "567,850"
    },
    {
        question: "Emal Fiza and Aamina are playing a quiz. For every 5 questions Aamina scores correctly, Emal scores one correct question. How many questions does Emal get correct if Aamina gets 70 questions correct?",
        choices: ["14", "23", "11", "50"],
        answer: "14"
    },
    {
        question: "If you have a straight line 3y = 6x+5; what is the gradient of the line?",
        choices: ["6", "2", "5", "18"],
        answer: "2"
    },
    {
        question: "What Is the y-intercept of the straight line of equation 3y = 6x+5?",
        choices: ["3", "6", "5", "1.7"],
        answer: "5"
    }
];

var generalQuestions = [{
        question: "Which chess piece is of the lowest theoretical value?",
        choices: ["Knight", "Castle", "Bishop", "Pawn"],
        answer: "Pawn"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the capital of Canada?",
        choices: ["Montreal", "Ottawa", "Toronto", "Vancouver"],
        answer: "Ottawa"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first man on the moon?",
        choices: ["Buzz Aldrin", "Yuri Gagarin", "Neil Armstrong", "John Glennr"],
        answer: "Neil Armstrong"
    },
    {
        question: "According to the Bible, what was the name of the town which was the birthplace of Jesus Christ?",
        choices: ["Nazareth", "Bethlehem", "Jerusalem", "Gethsemane"],
        answer: "Bethlehem"
    },
    {
        question: "What number is represented by the letters XIX in Roman numerals?",
        choices: ["19", "16", "11", "21"],
        answer: "19"
    },
    {
        question: "Name the third known major planet from the sun in our solar system.",
        choices: ["Venus", "Jupiter", "Mars", "Earth"],
        answer: "Earth"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the biggest living fish in the ocean?",
        choices: ["white shark", "Whale", "Tuna", "Barracuda"],
        answer: "Whale"
    },
    {
        question: "In which African country is Timbuktu?",
        choices: ["Algeria", "Chad", "Mali", "Nigeria"],
        answer: "Mali"
    },
    {
        question: "Name the traditional and popular wrestling sport of Japan.",
        choices: ["Sumo", "Origami", "Ikebana", "NKendo"],
        answer: "Sumo"
    },
    {
        question: "Name the capital of Australia.",
        choices: ["Melbourne", "Sydney", "Perth", "Canberra"],
        answer: "Canberra"
    }
];
